Gleb Polushkin

Software Engineer at Akvelon

gleb.proll@gmail.com

Summary

11+ years of professional experience in web development. I'm a passionate and self-motivated front-end developer and I pay a lot attention to latest Javascript and browsers trends as SPA, Virtual DOM. Not only concentrating on the technical part of the job, but also on the process and reaching the project's goals.

Beloved conceptions: HTML5 and its gorgeous APIs, CSS3, LESS/Stylus, Vanilla JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, BackboneJS, React, Git, Grunt, NodeJS, W3C, progressive enhancement, mobile browser optimisation and continuous integration technics.

Experience

Software Engineer at Akvelon

November 2015 - Present (7 months)

Akvelon was founded in 2000 to provide superior IT consulting and software development services. Akvelon's clients range from tiny start-ups to global corporations.

- Contributed to Microsoft Power BI project
- Automated and refactored review process of Custom Visuals for Microsoft Power Bi Custom Visuals gallery
- Developed validation tool for Power Bi Custom Visuals which validates, tests and checks for potential insecure javascript and harmful css

Senior Front-end developer at Lazada Group

June 2015 - November 2015 (6 months)

Lazada is Southeast Asia's No. 1 Online Shopping and Selling Destination

Operationally launched in March 2012, Lazada is Southeast Asia's number one online shopping and selling destination, with presence in Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam. Lazada also has offices in Hong Kong, Korea, United Kingdom and Russia.

- Refactored mobile version 6 regional Lazada sites (http://lazada.vn , http://lazada.co.id etc.)
- Implemented CSS regression testing tool. It helped with automation testing of releases and increase stability of revamps.

- Implemented multi-sprite builder task inside project Grunt and then Gulp builder for raster and vector (svg) icons.
- Implemented ESLint-controlled Javascript code style into the Lazada public site project

Senior Front-end developer at iMobilco

May 2014 - June 2015 (1 year 2 months)

iMobilco is a distributer and a publisher of ebooks, magazines and music.

- Support a content service http://imobilco.ru using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap+LESS, Javascript, BackboneJS, lodash.js, handlebars.js.
- Refactored front-end building system using NodeJS, Grunt, Yeoman.
- Developed client proxy for front-end developers with partial loading server side HTML and client side JS, CSS and images.
- Integrated Google Analytics eCommerce API, that turned over service auditory valuation

Senior Front-end developer at WeHeartPics

February 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 3 months)

We Heart Pics is the only fully-functional, photo-powered, social network. They enable people to communicate without relying on a mutual language or location.

- Developed Responsive Mobile-ready Single-page web applications with templating on client side.
- Developed responsive web application using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap+LESS, SVG, HTML5 APIs (Canvas API, Geo API), Javascript, BackboneJS, lodash.js, handlebars.js
- Developed build system using NodeJS, Grunt, Imagemagick, UglifyJS, JSHint, CSSMin, HTMLMin, ImageMin, NodeSprite.
- Developed
- Rewrote Open GL ES 2.0 shaders from mobile app to flash AGAL shaders.
- Rewrote the shaders to Javascript Canvas shader programs working on Webworkers.
- Developed proxy server using NodeJS, PhantomJS that made possible Search bot to crawl the dynamic ajax sites.
- Used Microformats and SEO best practices for photos, products.
- Used oEmbed for videos.
- Fixed existing markup according W3C stardards.

Front-end developer at BigBuzzy.ru

November 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 3 months)

BigBuzzy is a Groupon-like service.

- Got a massive expertise in HTML pixel perfect layout.
- Applied Mobile-first and Progress Enhancement principles.

- Developed progress-enhancement-based mobile version of http://bigbuzzy.ru http://bigbuzzy.ru/m/ using modernizer.js, jQuery, lodash.js, CSS3, MediaQueries.
- Researched and rewrote best parts of jQueryMobile on the mobile site.
- Tested the mobile site and made all usecases feasible on a wide row of mobile operation systems (Nokia Symbian, Windows Phone, Android 1.6-3.0, IOS)
- Created Freemarker(FTL) templates kit of block macros, layout macros, functions and utilities.
- Rewrote templates from XSLT to Freemarker reaching best performance on new Java architecture
- Developed layout builder for email newsletters with that horrible HTML4
- Fixed existing markup according W3C standards.

Senior Front-end Developer at SM & Partners

December 2008 - November 2011 (3 years)

SM & Partners is a development company. Creation and Accompaniment high-load web projects like business-oriented social networking services, dating and hr networking services.

- Developed RPG in-browser game for kids using Javascript, jQuery, CSS, Flash, PHP, MySQL.
- Created and debugged internet browser based on Firefox with a parental control extension on XUL.
- Architected a server software using Python and Blender3D for fast prerendering and rendering animations of game characters.
- Developed service for accounting game character outfits and animations with PSD parsing, management of artist's works, and XML configs generation using Javascript, jQuery, psd.js, NodeJS, PHP, MySQL, imagemagick
- Used to be an instant scrum master in front-end team of 5 members.
- Developed the video coder software based on FFMPEG and PHP on serverside as part of blogs social network http://f5.ru

Web Developer at Mediatoday

March 2008 - December 2008 (10 months)

Mediatoday is a full-service digital agency

- Developed and supported a full imdb-like service with online reservation eticket with PHP, MySQL
- Developed front-end part of the service using HTML4, CSS, Javascript, jQuery and Flash plus Papervision3d for the eticket reservation module.
- Developed PHP bot synchronizing schedules and reservations from each connected cinema.

Web Developer at BellIntegrator

October 2005 - March 2008 (2 years 6 months)

Bell Integrator is a global consulting, technology services, and outsourcing company that offers business critical solutions that resolve your most complex IT and business needs for top-tier telecom, finance, transportation, and healthcare enterprises.

- Developed the graphic charts modules (plain tree chart with the backpack algorithm and other trees, pies, bars etc.) for monitoring systems.
- Got a huge experience in Javascript, Actionscript and enterprise development.
- Utilized tricks for aggregating and displaying really big data on really slow client's computers.

Publications

2.5D games and feature of multiplayer game development

Highload++ Conference October 28, 2010

Authors: Gleb Polushkin

It's my report for Highload++ Conference 2010 - a review of servers and client technologies plus frameworks for multiplayer browser games. There I presented SmartFox Server as the best solution for that time.

Mobile Front-end development blog

http://blog.prolll.com/

Authors: Gleb Polushkin

My blog in Russian is about Mobile Front-end development. Quite often I need to write down and share an unknown mobile browser feature so this blog is designed for this.

Projects

Qstoq.me

May 2013 to September 2014

Members: Gleb Polushkin, Dmitry Shilyaev, Vladimir Gorshkov

Get payments online for what ever and where ever you want

Qstoq — it is a platform for creating price tags and getting payments for your digital content or real goods and services

Front-end is based on Backbone.JS, Bootstrap+LESS, handlebars.

Back-end Qstoq RESTful API is based on PHP, Yii and MySQL.

Small pitch about our API

http://www.slideshare.net/dsqstoq/qstoq-bs04

stylogram.com

January 2013 to January 2014

Members: Gleb Polushkin, Dmitry Kozachenok

Boston, USA based startup project with an idea of the personal fashion advisers from the USA for russian woman.

Front-end is based on backbone.js, bootstrap+less.

Back-end is PHP and MySQL.

boodoo.ru

December 2008 to November 2011

Members:Gleb Polushkin, Serge Kuzmenko

Social network for kids and browser with parent control

Certifications

Developing Innovative Ideas for New Companies: The First Step in Entrepreneurship

Coursera April 2014

Google Analytics Platform Principles

Google License fc7fe77b83034f0cb2ca4acd7f4d447b March 2014

Startup Engineering

Coursera September 2013

MCTS Microsoft SQL Server

2007

Languages

English (Professional working proficiency)

Russian (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

JavaScript

Backbone.js

React

jQuery

jQuery Mobile

Node.js

HTML5

CSS

LESS

Stylus

SASS

SVG

Web Applications

MySQL

Web Standards

PHP

AGAL

Freemarker

Handlebars

AMD

LMD

Git

JSON XML Front-end Typescript D3.js

Education

Vyatka State Technical University

Master's Degree, Computer Science, 2000 - 2005

Interests

Entrepreneurship, GFX, New Technologies

Gleb Polushkin

Software Engineer at Akvelon

gleb.proll@gmail.com



2 people have recommended Gleb

"I've been working with Gleb as Developer Relations Manager in Lazada Group for more than 6 months. Working together Gleb he has demonstrated both high quality refactoring of our legacy code base and writing high quality code from the scratch. As a top notch web developer Gleb has helped to improve our core framework and shared his deep knowledge with other web-developers. He is self-motivated and reliable expert who is always up to date with all updates in the area of JS, BackboneJS, ReactJS, SPA and other front-end trends. We are Mobile First company and Gleb has helped us to achieve enormous progress by his commitment in mobile browsing experience of our customers."

— Alexander Ptitsyn, Employee Relations Manager, Lazada Group, worked directly with Gleb at Lazada Group

"I worked with Gleb on BigBuzzy, Imobilco and Iphones.ru. The results were always great. He's one of those professionals who really stand for the project — with great attention to detail and perfectionism in a good way. Gleb's huge expertise in modern frontend helps him to find great and practical solutions for any development challenge we encounter. When he works on a project, I'm confident that its frontend part will be all right. And he's a great team player —always open and helpful. His valuable advice on anything about web development supported me countless times."

— **Denis Drozhzhov**, Art Director, Bigbuzzy, worked directly with Gleb at BigBuzzy.ru

Contact Gleb on LinkedIn